coldwellbankermoves.com 2018-09-09

# Privacy Statement - ColdwellBankerHomes.com

_Last Modified:  June 2, 2015_

NRT LLC operates this web site at coldwellbankerhomes.com (“Site”).  We respect the privacy of each user of the Site (referred to as "you"), whether you are just beginning your real estate search or have previously visited our Site.  This Privacy Statement gives you specific information about how we protect your privacy, how we treat your Personal Information, and how we use aggregated information.

**BY REGISTERING FOR OR USING THE SITE, YOU SIGNIFY YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT.   IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT, YOU CANNOT USE THE SITE. ** We reserve the right to modify this statement at any time by posting a notice on the Site’s home page.  (If we consider it appropriate, we may also provide additional notice of significant changes.)  Your use of the Site after the date of the last modification listed at the beginning of this Privacy Statement indicates to us that you agree to the changes.

## **Scope of this Privacy Statement**

This Privacy Statement applies to your use of this Site only.

The Site contains links to third-party web sites.  When you click on those links, you will go to a third-party site where you will be subject to that site’s privacy statement and we encourage you to read that policy statement.  Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those other web sites and we expressly disclaim any liability for their actions, including actions relating to the use and disclosure of Personal Information by those third parties. 

## 1\. What is Personal Information?

Personal Information is information collected online by us that identifies the person to whom such information pertains, including without limitation: name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address.

## 2\. Collection and Use of Your Information

### 2(a) Personal Information

We collect your Personal Information on the Site only when submitted by you in order to enhance the services we offer you.  
 **  
Do Not Track Signals** Do Not Track mechanisms or signals (“DNT signals”) enable a consumer to request the disabling of the tracking of their online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services.  As permitted by law, we do not permit the disabling of DNT signals.

### **2(b) Non-Personal Information**

Even if you do not send us any Personal Information, we collect information about how you use our site (“Non-Personal Information”). This information cannot be used to identify you personally and is explained in more detail below.

**What is Non-Personal Information?**

Like many sites, we obtain Non-Personal Information, such as: IP (internet protocol) addresses, browser types, the name of a user’s ISP (internet service provider), information about where a user comes from before arriving at our Site, what pages a user visits, the order of those pages, and the amount of time spent on each.  A vendor performs this service for us by sending a cookie to gather this information, compile it, and report to us. 

**Use of Non-Personal Information**

We use Non-Personal Information to customize the advertising and content you see, improve our services, conduct research, and provide anonymous aggregated reporting for internal audits and third-parties.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small data file, often including an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent from a web site's computer and stored on your computer's hard drive. Use of cookies is common on the Internet. A web site can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser permits a web site to access only the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is sent. (Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.) You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent. But if you refuse cookies, some parts of the Site will not function properly and may not provide services or information you have requested. For example, without cookies, we will not be able to provide you with searches that you have asked us to save.

**Hotjar**

We use [Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users' experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address, captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website. Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out). 

### 2(c) Use of Information With Respect to Third Parties

We reserve the right to share your Personal Information with our affiliated companies and marketing partners, as permitted by law, in order to fulfill our commitment of providing you with full service real estate brokerage services. 

In addition, we do share your Personal Information under the following circumstances:

A. Third party vendors we engage to provide services on our behalf, such as hosting, web-site development, and support, have access to Personal Information, but they have agreed not to disclose the Personal Information or to use it for any purpose other than providing the requested services.

B. There may arise special circumstances where it is necessary for us to disclose and use Personal Information and Non-Personal Information, such as: to enforce this Privacy Statement or any other part of our Terms of Use; to protect our property or rights; to protect the safety of anyone; to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding possible illegal or improper activities; to carry out a merger or consolidation with another entity, a sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, or any similar transaction; or for other reasons we determine in good faith are necessary, appropriate, or required by law, such as when we respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal or administrative process, or in coordination with law enforcement.

## 3. Location of Servers and Transfer of Information to the United States

The Site is hosted by servers in the United States, and, as such, the Site is governed by United States law.  If you are located outside of the United States, your Personal Information will be transferred to the United States.  By submitting your Personal Information, you consent to its transfer to the United States and to its storage, processing, and use there in accordance with this Privacy Statement and United States law.

## 4\. Security

Our hosting service maintains its systems in accordance with reasonable industry standards to reasonably secure the information of its customers against unauthorized access, accidental or intentional manipulation, and loss.  However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and you use the Site at your own risk.

## 5\. California Residents

Under California law, California residents have the right to request in writing from businesses with whom they have an established business relationship (1) a list of categories of personal information, such as name, address, e-mail address, and the type of services provided to the customer, that a business has disclosed to third parties (including affiliates that are separate legal entities) during the immediately preceding calendar year for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes and (2) the names and addresses of all such third parties.

To request the above information please contact us.

We will respond to such requests within 30 days of receipt. Please note that we are only required to respond to each customer once per calendar year.

## 6\. Children

This Site is not directed to children under the age of 13 (“Children”), and we do not knowingly collect any information, including Personal Information, from Children. 

## 7\. Correction/Updating Personal Information

If your Personal Information changes or if you no longer wish to use the Site, you may correct or update your Personal Information or unsubscribe from any email alert services you have requested by modifying or deleting your profile on the Site.

## 8\. Comments and Questions

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement, please use the Contact Us form on coldwellbankerhomes.com.
